export const QUESTIONS = [
  {
    // Question 1
    question: `What was Sarah's reaction to the news that she would bear a son?`,
    answers: [`She laughed`, `She cried`, `She rejoiced`, `She fainted`],
    correctAnswer: `She laughed`,
    bibleText: `Genesis 18:12-13`,
  },
  {
    // Question 2
    question: `Who was NOT one of the three Hebrew boys cast into the fiery furnace?`,
    answers: [`Shadrach`, `Meshach`, `Abednego`, `Daniel`],
    correctAnswer: `Daniel`,
    bibleText: `Daniel 3:20`,
  },
  {
    // Question 3
    question: `Who was David's best friend?`,
    answers: [`Jonathan`, `Saul`, `Samuel`, `Goliath`],
    correctAnswer: `Jonathan`,
    bibleText: `1 Samuel 20:42`,
  },
  {
    // Question 4
    question: `Who lodged the spies in Jericho?`,
    answers: [`Leah`, `Rehab`, `Mariam`, `Jezebel`],
    correctAnswer: `Solomon`,
    bibleText: `Joshua 2:1`,
  },
  {
    // Question 5
    question: `Who was cast into a den of lions?`,
    answers: [`Daniel`, `Joseph`, `Elisha`, `Job`],
    correctAnswer: `Daniel`,
    bibleText: `Daniel 6:16`,
  },
  {
    // Question 6
    question: `Where was Jesus mostly raised as a child?`,
    answers: [`Jerusalem`, `Bethlehem`, `Nazareth`, `Egypt`],
    correctAnswer: `Nazareth`,
    bibleText: `Matthew 2:23`,
  },
  {
    // Question 7
    question: `What was the 12-year-old Jesus doing when His parents found Him?`,
    answers: [
      `Praying to His Father`,
      `Fishing with nets`,
      `Teaching in the temple`,
      `Playing with other kids`,
    ],
    correctAnswer: `Teaching in the temple`,
    bibleText: `Luke 2:46-47`,
  },
  {
    // Question 8
    question: `What happened immediately after Peter denied Christ three times?`,
    answers: [
      `Peter fell dead`,
      `The ground shook`,
      `Peter went blind`,
      `A rooster crowed`,
    ],
    correctAnswer: `A rooster crowed`,
    bibleText: `Matthew 26:74`,
  },
  {
    // Question 9
    question: `At the moment Jesus died on the cross, which of the following things did NOT happen?`,
    answers: [
      `Earthquake`,
      `Jesus came to life`,
      `Dead came to life`,
      `Temple veil was torn`,
    ],
    correctAnswer: `Jesus came to life`,
    bibleText: `Matthew 27:51-53`,
  },
  {
    // Question 10
    question: `What animal attacked Paul after being shipwrecked on the island of Malta?`,
    answers: [`Snake`, `Bear`, `Mule`, `Scorpion`],
    correctAnswer: `Snake`,
    bibleText: `Acts 28:3`,
  },
  {
    // Question 11
    question: `Who were the first disciples called by Jesus`,
    answers: [
      `Peter and John`,
      `Peter and Andrew`,
      `Phillip and John`,
      `Andrew and John`,
    ],
    correctAnswer: `Peter and Andrew`,
    bibleText: `Matthew 4:18-22`,
  },
  {
    // Question 12
    question: `Paul was shipwrecked on what island`,
    answers: [`Malta`, `Patmos`, `Camel`, `Greece`],
    correctAnswer: `Malta`,
    bibleText: `Act 27:1-28`,
  },
  {
    // Question 13
    question: `Who recognized Jesus as messiah when he was presented to the temple as a baby?`,
    answers: [`Wise men`, `John the baptist`, `Anna`, `Simeon`],
    correctAnswer: `Simeon`,
    bibleText: `Luke 2 :22-23`,
  },
  {
    // Question 14
    question: `Who is the high priest  of Jerusalem that put Jesus on trial?`,
    answers: [`Agrippa`, `Pilate`, `Cephas`, `Caiaphas`],
    correctAnswer: `Caiaphas`,
    bibleText: `Matt 25 : 56-67`,
  },
  {
    // Question 13
    question: `Which disciples doubts jesus' ressurrection untill he see jesus with his own eyes?`,
    answers: [`James`, `Thomas`, `Philip`, `Peter`],
    correctAnswer: `Thomas`,
    bibleText: `John 20:24-29`,
  },
  {
    // Question 14
    question: `How many people entered Noah's ark?`,
    answers: [`12`, `10`, `8`, `9`],
    correctAnswer: `8`,
    bibleText: `Gen 7:13`,
  },
  {
    // Question 15
    question: `Paul was shipwrecked on what island?`,
    answers: [`Malta`, `Patmos`, `Camel`, `Greece`],
    correctAnswer: `Malta`,
    bibleText: `Act 27:1-28`,
  },
  {
    // Question 16
    question: `What did God create on the fourth day?`,
    answers: [`Firmament`, `Trees`, `Sun, moon and stars`, `Animals`],
    correctAnswer: `Sun, moon and stars`,
    bibleText: `Gen 1 : 14-16`,
  },
  {
    // Question 17
    question: `Who is the first murderer in the bible?`,
    answers: [`Seth`, `Adam`, `Abel`, `Cain`],
    correctAnswer: `Cain`,
    bibleText: `Act 27:1-28`,
  },
  {
    // Question 18
    question: `Which place is called 'Zion' and ' the city of David'?`,
    answers: [`Cannaan`, `Rome`, `Jerusalem`, `Nazareth`],
    correctAnswer: `Jerusalem`,
    bibleText: `2 samuel 5:9`,
  },
  {
    // Question 19
    question: `Which disciple walked on water?`,
    answers: [`Peter`, `James`, `John`, `Philip`],
    correctAnswer: `Peter`,
    bibleText: `Matt 14 : 22-31`,
  },
  {
    // Question 20
    question: `How many days did it take God to create the world?`,
    answers: [`S6`, `9`, `7`, `8`],
    correctAnswer: `6`,
    bibleText: `Gen 2:2`,
  },
  {
    // Question 21
    question: `Where did god give moses the ten commandment?`,
    answers: [`Mount Patmos`, `Mount Harat`, `Mount Camel`, `mount Sinai`],
    correctAnswer: `Mount Sinai`,
    bibleText: `Exodus 19: 1-40`,
  },
  {
    // Question 22
    question: `What golden image did the isrealites make mount Sinai?`,
    answers: [
      `A golden Calf`,
      `A golden sheep`,
      `A golden sheep`,
      `A golden Cow`,
    ],
    correctAnswer: `A golden calf`,
    bibleText: `Exodus 32`,
  },
  {
    // Question 23
    question: `Who was the woman judge who led isreal to victory?`,
    answers: [`Abigail`, `Nariam`, `Anna`, `Deborah`],
    correctAnswer: `Deborah`,
    bibleText: `Judges 4`,
  },
  {
    // Question 24
    question: `With what did samson killed 1,000 Philistines?`,
    answers: [
      `A Sword`,
      `A lion jawbone`,
      `A donkey jawbone`,
      `A  cow jawbone`,
    ],
    correctAnswer: `A donkey jawbone`,
    bibleText: `Judges 15: 19`,
  },
  {
    // Question 25
    question: `When David wanted to fight goliath, what did saul try to give him?`,
    answers: [`Sling`, `Shield`, `Armour`, `Sword`],
    correctAnswer: `Armour`,
    bibleText: `! samuel 17`,
  },
  {
    // Question 26
    question: `What did david take from the brook to fight Goliagth?`,
    answers: [`6 stones`, `5 stones`, `4 stones`, `3 stones`],
    correctAnswer: `5 stones`,
    bibleText: ` 1 samuel 17: 26-50`,
  },
  {
    // Question 27
    question: `What country did David run away to when Saul wanted to kill him?`,
    answers: [`Gibeon`, `Babylon`, `Philistines`, `Canaan`],
    correctAnswer: `Philistines`,
    bibleText: `1 samuel 21 :10`,
  },
  {
    // Question 28
    question: `How many times did David spared Saul's life?`,
    answers: [`4 times`, `once`, `thrice`, `twice`],
    correctAnswer: `twice`,
    bibleText: `1 samuel 24 and 26`,
  },
  {
    // Question 29
    question: `Who was the captain of David army?`,
    answers: [`Jael`, `Ahitophel`, `Abinadab`, `Joab`],
    correctAnswer: `Joab`,
    bibleText: `2 samuel 24 : 2`,
  },
  {
    // Question 30
    question: `Which woman did David commit adultery with?`,
    answers: [`Ahinoam`, `Mariam`, `Bethsheba`, `Abigail`],
    correctAnswer: `Bethsheba`,
    bibleText: ` 2 samuel 11`,
  },

  {
    // Question 30
    question: `Which woman did David commit adultery with?`,
    answers: [`Ahinoam`, `Mariam`, `Bethsheba`, `Abigail`],
    correctAnswer: `Bethsheba`,
    bibleText: ` 2 samuel 11`,
  },
  {
    // Question 31
    question: `What prophet came to rebuke David?`,
    answers: [`Elijah`, `Elisha`, `Nathan`, `Samuel`],
    correctAnswer: `Nathan`,
    bibleText: ` 2 samuel 12`,
  },
  {
    // Question 32
    question: `Who was David son that started a rebelion against him?`,
    answers: [`Absalom`, `Uriah`, `Adonijah`, `Reuben`],
    correctAnswer: `Absalom`,
    bibleText: ` 2 samuel 15`,
  },
  {
    // Question 33
    question: `What famous queen  came to visit Solomon?`,
    answers: [
      `Queen of Jerusalem`,
      `Queen of Cannaan`,
      `Queen of Babylon`,
      `Queen of sheba`,
    ],
    correctAnswer: `Queen of sheba`,
    bibleText: ` 1 kings 10`,
  },
  {
    // Question 34
    question: `Who was the last king Daniel served under?`,
    answers: [`Meshac`, `Jarius`, `Nebuchadnezzer`, `Darius`],
    correctAnswer: `Darius`,
    bibleText: ` Daniel 6 : 1- 28`,
  },
  {
    // Question 35
    question: `What were the babylonian names of Daniel 3 friends?`,
    answers: [
      `Meshach,Caleb and Abednego`,
      `Abednego, Shadrach and Joab`,
      `Jael, Shadrach and Meshach`,
      `Shadrach, Meshach and Abednego`,
    ],
    correctAnswer: `Shadrach, Meshach and Abednego`,
    bibleText: ` Daniel 3 : 8-30`,
  },
  {
    // Question 36
    question: `Who returned to isreal to build the walls of Jerusalem?`,
    answers: [`Habakkuk`, `Hosea`, `Zacharia`, `Nehemiah`],
    correctAnswer: `Nehemiah`,
    bibleText: ` Nehemiah 1`,
  },
  {
    // Question 37
    question: `Name the City Jesus was born?`,
    answers: [`Zion`, `Bethlehem`, `Jerusalem`, `Nazareth`],
    correctAnswer: `Bethelehem`,
    bibleText: `Matthew 2 :1`,
  },
  {
    // Question 38
    question: `Name Jesus hometown?`,
    answers: [`Zion`, `Bethlehem`, `Jerusalem`, `Nazareth`],
    correctAnswer: `Nazareth`,
    bibleText: ` Luke 4 :16`,
  },
  {
    // Question 39
    question: `How many days was Lazarus dead before Jesus came to visit?`,
    answers: [`5 days`, `2 days`, `3 days`, `4 days`],
    correctAnswer: `4 days`,
    bibleText: `John 11 :17`,
  },
  {
    // Question 40
    question: `Whats the name of the demon Jesus cast out in the region of  Gerasenes?`,
    answers: [`Belial`, `Persia`, `Belzubub`, `legion`],
    correctAnswer: `Legion`,
    bibleText: ` Mark 5 : 1-20`,
  },
  {
    // Question 41
    question: `Name the two old testament people who appeared when Jesus was transfigured?`,
    answers: [
      `Moses and David`,
      `Elijah and Elisha`,
      `Moses and Elijah`,
      `Moses and Elisha`,
    ],
    correctAnswer: `Moses and Elijah`,
    bibleText: ` Matthew 17:3`,
  },
  {
    // Question 42
    question: `Who is the Roman governor who sat over Jesus trial?`,
    answers: [`Herodias`, `Cornelius`, `Herod`, `Pilate`],
    correctAnswer: `Pilate`,
    bibleText: ` Matthew 27:2`,
  },

  {
    // Question 43
    question: `Who preached at pentecost?`,
    answers: [`James`, `Paul`, `John`, `Peter`],
    correctAnswer: `Peter`,
    bibleText: ` Acts 2 : 14-41`,
  },

  {
    // Question 44
    question: `Which apotle shared the Gospel with an Ethiopian official on the road to Gaza?`,
    answers: [`Stephen`, `Paul`, `Peter`, `Philip`],
    correctAnswer: `Philip`,
    bibleText: ` Acts 8 :28-40`,
  },

  {
    // Question 45
    question: `In what city were Jesus followers first called christian?`,
    answers: [`Jerusalem`, `Antioch`, `Rome`, `Carpaunum`],
    correctAnswer: `Antioch`,
    bibleText: ` Acts 11 :26`,
  },

  {
    // Question 46
    question: `Who were Noah's three sons?`,
    answers: [
      `Japheth, Seth and Abel`,
      `Abel, Shem and Ham`,
      `Ham, Abel and Japheth`,
      `Shem,Ham and Japheth`,
    ],
    correctAnswer: `Shem, Ham and Japheth`,
    bibleText: ` Gen 9 :23`,
  },

  {
    // Question 47
    question: `Who asked for Jesus body after he was crucified?`,
    answers: [
      `Joseph of Arimathea`,
      `Joseph of Bethlehem`,
      `Joseph of Ethiopia`,
      `Joseph of Nazareth`,
    ],
    correctAnswer: `Joseph of Arimathea  `,
    bibleText: ` Matthew 15 :43 `,
  },
  {
    // Question 48
    question: `Who wrote the book of revelation?`,
    answers: [`Peter`, `Paul`, `John`, `Timothy`],
    correctAnswer: `John  `,
    bibleText: ` Revelation 1 : 4 `,
  },
  {
    // Question 49
    question: `Who worked as a tax collector prior to becoming a disciple?`,
    answers: [`Matthew`, `Philip`, `Andrew`, `Batholomew`],
    correctAnswer: `Matthew`,
    bibleText: ` Matthew 9 : 9-13`,
  },
  {
    // Question 50
    question: `What is the name of the village where Jesus turned water to wine?`,
    answers: [
      `Cana of Jerusalel`,
      `Canaan of Nazareth`,
      `Jerusalem`,
      `Cana of Galilee`,
    ],
    correctAnswer: `Cana of Galilee`,
    bibleText: ` John 2 : 11`,
  },
  {
    // Question 51
    question: `Which prophet is known for turning his rod into a bronze snake?`,
    answers: [`Aaron`, `Elijah`, `Moses`, `Samuel`],
    correctAnswer: `Moses`,
    bibleText: ` Exodus 4 :2`,
  },
  {
    // Question 52
    question: `What did God divide when he created the earth?`,
    answers: [
      `The light from darkness`,
      `The moon from star`,
      `Water from land`,
      `Ocean from land`,
    ],
    correctAnswer: `The light from darkness`,
    bibleText: `Gen 1 :4`,
  },
  {
    // Question 53
    question: `Who among these was the wife of Jacob?`,
    answers: [`Leah`, `Rebekah`, `Dinar`, `Tabitha`],
    correctAnswer: `Leah`,
    bibleText: ` Gen 29 : 17`,
  },
  {
    // Question 54
    question: `What is the name of the first queen of Xerxes?`,
    answers: [`Esther`, `Jezebel`, `Vashti`, `Abigail`],
    correctAnswer: `Vashti`,
    bibleText: ` Esther 1`,
  },

  {
    // Question 55
    question: `What was the hebrew name of Esther?`,
    answers: [`Beulah`, `Havilla`, `Ruby`, `Hadassah`],
    correctAnswer: `Hadassah`,
    bibleText: ` Esther 2 :7`,
  },

  {
    // Question 56
    question: `Who was the father of Samuel?`,
    answers: [`Nimrod`, `Abinadab`, `Elkanah`, `Jesse`],
    correctAnswer: `Elkanah`,
    bibleText: ` 1 samuel 1 :1`,
  },

  {
    // Question 57
    question: `After the philistines captured the ark of God, they took it from Ebenezer to where?`,
    answers: [`Gibeon`, `Gilead`, `Jerusalem`, `Ashdod`],
    correctAnswer: `Ashdod`,
    bibleText: `1 samuel 5 : 1`,
  },
  {
    // Question 58
    question: `What was the name of Samuel's first born?`,
    answers: [`Joab`, `Jephtah`, `Joel`, `Jonah`],
    correctAnswer: `Joel`,
    bibleText: ` 1 samuel 8 : 2`,
  },

  {
    // Question 59
    question: `Whats the name of Saul's daughter that married David?`,
    answers: [`Abiel`, `Kish`, `Michal`, `Dorcas`],
    correctAnswer: `Michal`,
    bibleText: ` 1 samuel 18; 20 `,
  },

  {
    // Question 60
    question: `What is the name of Nabal's wife?`,
    answers: [`Mariam`, `Anna`, `Bethsheba`, `Abigail`],
    correctAnswer: `Abigail`,
    bibleText: ` 1 samuel 25 `,
  },

  {
    // Question 61
    question: `Samuel is after which book of the bible?`,
    answers: [`Ruth`, `Joshua`, `Chronicles`, `Judges`],
    correctAnswer: `Ruth`,
    bibleText: ` 1 samuel 1 `,
  },

  {
    // Question 62
    question: `How many sons did Jesse have?`,
    answers: [`12`, `5`, `9`, `8`],
    correctAnswer: `8`,
    bibleText: ` 1 samuel 17:40 `,
  },
  {
    // Question 63
    question: `The account of Adam and Eve's disobedience was recorded in what chapter in Genesis?`,
    answers: [`4`, `3`, `2`, `1`],
    correctAnswer: `3`,
    bibleText: ` Genesis 3 `,
  },

  {
    // Question 64
    question: `How old was Methuselah before he died?`,
    answers: [`965`, `967`, `968`, `969`],
    correctAnswer: `969`,
    bibleText: ` Genesis 5 : 27 `,
  },

  {
    // Question 65
    question: `Adam lived for how many years?`,
    answers: [`900 years`, `920 years`, `940 years`, `930years`],
    correctAnswer: `930 years`,
    bibleText: ` Genesis 5 : 5 `,
  },
  {
    // Question 66
    question: `The ark of Noah rested on which mountain?`,
    answers: [`Patmos`, `Ura`, `Camel`, `Ararat`],
    correctAnswer: `Ararat`,
    bibleText: ` Genesis 8 :4 `,
  },

  {
    // Question 67
    question: `How many wives did Jacob have?`,
    answers: [`4`, `3`, `1`, `2`],
    correctAnswer: `2`,
    bibleText: ` Genesis 30 `,
  },

  {
    // Question 68
    question: `Who was the father of Abraham?`,
    answers: [`Terah`, `Nimrod`, `Laban`, `Abimelek`],
    correctAnswer: `Terah`,
    bibleText: `Genesis 11:26 `,
  },

  {
    // Question 69
    question: `What is the name of Jacob only daughter?`,
    answers: [`Dinar`, `Leah`, `Dianna`, `Suzzanna`],
    correctAnswer: `Dinar`,
    bibleText: ` Genesis 34 :1 `,
  },

  {
    // Question 70
    question: `What is the name of Moses first son?`,
    answers: [`Jochebed`, `Jethro`, `Gerar`, `Gershom`],
    correctAnswer: `Gershom`,
    bibleText: ` Exodus 2 : 22 `,
  },
  {
    // Question 71
    question: `What is the name of Naomi's husband who died?`,
    answers: [`Elimelech`, `Gera`, `Edom`, `Obed`],
    correctAnswer: `Elimelech`,
    bibleText: ` Ruth 1 : 2 `,
  },

  {
    // Question 72
    question: `What nationality is Ruth?`,
    answers: [`Judea`, `Moabite`, `Jerusalem`, `Isreal`],
    correctAnswer: `Moabite`,
    bibleText: ` Ruth 1 : 22 `,
  },

  {
    // Question 73
    question: `What was the name of  Naomi's other daughter-in-law, besides ruth?`,
    answers: [`Dianna`, `Oma`, `Oprah`, `Orpha`],
    correctAnswer: `Orpha`,
    bibleText: ` Ruth 2 : 9 `,
  },

  {
    // Question 74
    question: `How many chapters are in the book of John?`,
    answers: [`22`, `18`, `21`, `20`],
    correctAnswer: `20`,
    bibleText: ` John 20 `,
  },

  {
    // Question 75
    question: `Who came to see Jesus night?`,
    answers: [`The Centurion`, `John`, `Nicodemus`, `Zacheus`],
    correctAnswer: `Nicodemus`,
    bibleText: ` John 3 :2 `,
  },
  {
    // Question 76
    question: `Jesus met the Samaritan woman at which well?`,
    answers: [`Abraham`, `Isaac`, `Jacob`, `David`],
    correctAnswer: `Jacob`,
    bibleText: ` John 4 : 6 `,
  },
  {
    // Question 77
    question: `The pool of Bethesda is located where?`,
    answers: [`Judea`, `Jerusalem`, `Samaria`, `Galilee`],
    correctAnswer: `Jerusalem`,
    bibleText: ` John 5 :1 `,
  },
  {
    // Question 78
    question: `Who was Simon Peter's brother?`,
    answers: [`John`, `judas`, `Andrew`, `James`],
    correctAnswer: `Andrew`,
    bibleText: ` John 6 :8`,
  },

  {
    // Question 79
    question: `What was the other name of Thomas?`,
    answers: [`Didomas`, `Didymos`, `Didymas`, `Didymus`],
    correctAnswer: `Didymus`,
    bibleText: ` John 11 :16 `,
  },
  {
    // Question 80
    question: `Who was released in exchange for Jesus?`,
    answers: [`Bernabba`, `Bahabas`, `Barnabas`, `Barabbas`],
    correctAnswer: `Barabbas`,
    bibleText: ` John 18 :40 `,
  },

  {
    // Question 81
    question: `Complete this Jesus statement: Sanctify them by the truth; your ____________ is truth`,
    answers: [`Grace`, `Sword`, `Word`, `Light`],
    correctAnswer: `Word`,
    bibleText: ` Johh 17 : 17 `,
  },

  {
    // Question 82
    question: `What is the meaning of Golgotha?  Place of  _______`,
    answers: [`Pain`, `Skin`, `Skull`, `Scalp`],
    correctAnswer: `Skull`,
    bibleText: ` John 19 : 7 `,
  },

  {
    // Question 83
    question: `The garment of Jesus was divided into ________`,
    answers: [`2`, `3`, `4`, `5`],
    correctAnswer: `4`,
    bibleText: ` John 19 : 23 `,
  },

  {
    // Question 84
    question: `Who was released in exchange for Jesus?`,
    answers: [`Bernabba`, `Bahabas`, `Barnabas`, `Barabbas`],
    correctAnswer: `Barabbas`,
    bibleText: ` John 18 :40 `,
  },

  {
    // Question 85
    question: `Who built a city named Enoch?`,
    answers: [`Seth`, `Adam`, `Cain`, `Abel`],
    correctAnswer: `Cain`,
    bibleText: ` Genesis 4 :17 `,
  },
  {
    // Question 86
    question: `Who was Keturah?`,
    answers: [
      `The wife of Esau`,
      `The wife of Abraham`,
      `The wife of Jacob`,
      `The wife of Isaac`,
    ],
    correctAnswer: `Abraham`,
    bibleText: ` Genesis 25 :1 `,
  },

  {
    // Question 87
    question: `Which one of the following is not one of Jacob's sons?`,
    answers: [`Reuben`, `Joseph`, `Zebulum`, `Naphtali`],
    correctAnswer: `Daniel`,
    bibleText: ` Genesis 35 :23-26 `,
  },
  {
    // Question 88
    question: `The name of the tribe appointed over the care of the terbanacle is?`,
    answers: [`Reuben`, `Zebullum`, `Judah`, `Levi`],
    correctAnswer: `Levi`,
    bibleText: ` Numbers 1 :50 `,
  },

  {
    // Question 89
    question: `Who was Joshua father?`,
    answers: [`Jethro`, `Nun`, `Moses`, `Aaron`],
    correctAnswer: `Nun`,
    bibleText: ` Joshua 1 :1 `,
  },

  {
    // Question 90
    question: `How many spies did Joshua send to Jericho?`,
    answers: [`3`, `10`, `2`, `12`],
    correctAnswer: `2`,
    bibleText: ` Joshua 2 :1 `,
  },

  {
    // Question 91
    question: `How many years did the children of Isreal walk in the wilderness?`,
    answers: [`40 years`, `50 years`, `60 years`, `45 years`],
    correctAnswer: `40 years`,
    bibleText: ` Joshua 5 : 16 `,
  },

  {
    // Question 92
    question: `Who took the devoted things of the lord in the camp of IIsreal?`,
    answers: [`Kiriath`, `Eleaxer`, `Issacha`, `Achan`],
    correctAnswer: `Achan`,
    bibleText: ` Joshua 7 :1 `,
  },

  {
    // Question 93
    question: `Where was the bones of Joseph buried?`,
    answers: [`Jericho`, `Gilgar`, `Nahor`, `Shechem`],
    correctAnswer: `Sheshem`,
    bibleText: ` Joshua 24 : 32 `,
  },

  {
    // Question 94
    question: `How many days did the children of Isreal marched around Jericho?`,
    answers: [`10 days`, `9 days`, `7 days`, `6 days`],
    correctAnswer: ` 6 days`,
    bibleText: ` Joshua 6 : 14 `,
  },

  {
    // Question 95
    question: `Who was the father of Ishbosheth?`,
    answers: [`Solomon`, `Johnathan`, `David`, `Saul`],
    correctAnswer: `Saul`,
    bibleText: ` 2 Samuel 2 : 10 `,
  },

  {
    // Question 96
    question: `Who was the first born of David?`,
    answers: [`Solomon`, `Adonijah`, `Amnon`, `Absalom`],
    correctAnswer: `Amnon`,
    bibleText: ` 2 Samuel 3 : 2 `,
  },

  {
    // Question 97
    question: `Who was the father of Mephibosheth?`,
    answers: [`Solomon`, `Johnathan`, `David`, `Ishbosheth`],
    correctAnswer: `Johnathan`,
    bibleText: ` 2 Samuel 4 : 5 `,
  },

  {
    // Question 98
    question: `How old was David when he was crowned king?`,
    answers: [`25`, `40`, `30`, `35`],
    correctAnswer: `30`,
    bibleText: ` 2 Samuel 5 : 4 `,
  },

  {
    // Question 99
    question: `The ark of the lord was taken to the house of who?`,
    answers: [`Abijah`, `Jephthar`, `Obed-Edom`, `Jabez`],
    correctAnswer: `Obed-Edom`,
    bibleText: ` 2 Samuel 6 :8 `,
  },

  {
    // Question 100
    question: `Ahithophel was David's _______ ?`,
    answers: [`Butler`, `Chef`, `Recorder`, `Counselor`],
    correctAnswer: `Counselor`,
    bibleText: ` 2 Samuel 5 : 31 `,
  },

  {
    // Question 101
    question: `1 Samuel is after which book of the bible ?`,
    answers: [`Judges`, `Ruth`, `2 Chronicles`, `2 Kings`],
    correctAnswer: `Ruth`,
    bibleText: ` 1 Samuel 1: 1 `,
  },

  {
    // Question 102
    question: `Who was the father of Samuel ?`,
    answers: [`Elkanah`, `Jesse`, `Gerar`, `Gibeon`],
    correctAnswer: `Elkanah`,
    bibleText: ` 1 Samuel 1 : 1 `,
  },

  {
    // Question 103
    question: `How many times did the lord call Samuel?`,
    answers: [`twice`, `Thrice`, `Once`, `4 times`],
    correctAnswer: `4 times`,
    bibleText: ` 1 Samuel 3  : 8-10 `,
  },

  {
    // Question 104
    question: `How old was Saul when he became king?`,
    answers: [`33 years`, `35 years`, `30 years`, `40 years`],
    correctAnswer: `30 years`,
    bibleText: ` 1 Samuel 13:1 `,
  },

  {
    // Question 105
    question: `Where was Goliathe from?`,
    answers: [`Philipi`, `Philistine`, `Philimon`, `Ehesus`],
    correctAnswer: `Philistine`,
    bibleText: ` 1 Samuel 17: 23 `,
  },

  {
    // Question 106
    question: `Who became the king of Isreal after David?`,
    answers: [`Jehosaphat`, `Ahab`, `Solomon`, `Jerobaom`],
    correctAnswer: `Solomon`,
    bibleText: ` 1 kings 2 : 12 `,
  },

  {
    // Question 107
    question: `What was the name of the Queen that visited Solomon?`,
    answers: [`Queen Deborah`, `Queen Mariam`, `Queen Sheba`, `Queen Amiral`],
    correctAnswer: `Queen Sheba`,
    bibleText: ` 1 kings 10 :1 `,
  },

  {
    // Question 108
    question: `Solomon had how many wives?`,
    answers: [`300`, `500`, `700`, `900`],
    correctAnswer: `700`,
    bibleText: ` 1 kings 11 :3 `,
  },

  {
    // Question 109
    question: `Who became Isreal king after king Solomon?`,
    answers: [`Rehoboam`, `Jeroboam`, `Ahab`, `Hezekiah`],
    correctAnswer: `Rehoboam`,
    bibleText: ` 1 kings 11 : 43 `,
  },

  {
    // Question 110
    question: `Where was Elijah from?`,
    answers: [`Judea`, `Jerusalem`, `Tishebe`, `Jericho`],
    correctAnswer: `Tishebe`,
    bibleText: ` 1 kings 17 :1 `,
  },

  {
    // Question 111
    question: `Who was the mother of Rehoboam?`,
    answers: [`Naamah`, `Elizabeth`, `Abigail`, `Bathshebah`],
    correctAnswer: `Naamah`,
    bibleText: ` 1 kings 14 :21 `,
  },

  {
    // Question 112
    question: `Who became the next king after Rehoboam?`,
    answers: [`Adonijah`, `Abijah`, `Abiram`, `Abijam`],
    correctAnswer: `Abijam`,
    bibleText: ` 1 kings 14 :31 `,
  },

  {
    // Question 113
    question: `Who was the wife of Ahab?`,
    answers: [`Vasthti`, `Jerusha`, `Jecoliah`, `Jezebel`],
    correctAnswer: `Jezebel`,
    bibleText: ` 1 kings 16 :31 `,
  },

  {
    // Question 114
    question: `What was the name of the birds that God sent to feed Elijah?`,
    answers: [`Hawk`, `Dove`, `Ravens`, `Eagle`],
    correctAnswer: `Ravens`,
    bibleText: ` 1 kings 17 :6 `,
  },

  {
    // Question 115
    question: `What was the name of the mountain that prophet Elijah challenged Ahab to?`,
    answers: [`Camel`, `Sinai`, `Tabor`, `Zion`],
    correctAnswer: `Camel`,
    bibleText: ` 1 kings 18 :17 `,
  },

  {
    // Question 116
    question: `Who rebelled against Isreal after king Ahabs death?`,
    answers: [`Nahor`, `Eli`, `Elijah`, `Moab`],
    correctAnswer: `Moab`,
    bibleText: ` 2kings 1:1 `,
  },

  {
    // Question 117
    question: `Who did Ahaziah consult when he had an injury?`,
    answers: [`Tor`, `Baal-Zebub`, `Og`, `Shion`],
    correctAnswer: `Baal-Zebub`,
    bibleText: ` 2kings 1:2 `,
  },

  {
    // Question 118
    question: `How many men went in search for Elijah when he eas taken to heaven?`,
    answers: [`40`, `30`, `50`, `20`],
    correctAnswer: `50`,
    bibleText: ` 2kings 2:17 `,
  },

  {
    // Question 119
    question: `Who was the father of Elisha?`,
    answers: [`Elijah`, `Shaphat`, `Nebat`, `Kish`],
    correctAnswer: `Shaphat`,
    bibleText: ` 2kings 3:11 `,
  },

  {
    // Question 200
    question: `What was the name of Elisha's servant?`,
    answers: [`Jael`, `Naaman`, `Elijah`, `Gehazi`],
    correctAnswer: `Gehazi`,
    bibleText: ` 2kings 4:12 `,
  },

  {
    // Question 201
    question: `Naaman suffered from what?`,
    answers: [`Leprosy`, `Blindness`, `Dermatitis`, `Deafness`],
    correctAnswer: `Leprosy`,
    bibleText: ` 2kings 5:1 `,
  },

  {
    // Question 202
    question: `How many times was Naaman asked to dip in the river?`,
    answers: [`7`, `8`, `9`, `3`],
    correctAnswer: `7`,
    bibleText: ` 2kings 5:9 `,
  },

  {
    // Question 203
    question: `How old was Joash when he began to rule?`,
    answers: [`7`, `8`, `9`, `12`],
    correctAnswer: `7`,
    bibleText: ` 2kings 11:21 `,
  },

  {
    // Question 204
    question: `Whose tomb brought a dead man to life?`,
    answers: [`Ezekiel`, `Eli`, `Elijah`, `Elisha`],
    correctAnswer: `Elisha`,
    bibleText: ` 2kings 13:21 `,
  },

  {
    // Question 205
    question: `How many elsers sat around the throne of heaven?`,
    answers: [`30`, `20`, `24`, `23`],
    correctAnswer: `24`,
    bibleText: ` Revelation 4 :4 `,
  },

  {
    // Question 206
    question: `Who rebelled against Isreal after king Ahabs death?`,
    answers: [`Nahor`, `Eli`, `Elijah`, `Moab`],
    correctAnswer: `Moab`,
    bibleText: ` 2kings 1:1 `,
  },
];
